<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
    <rss version="2.0">
    
    <channel>
      <title>Eduardo Zepeda's Personal Site</title>
      <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev</link>
      <description>Eduardo Zepeda web developer personal site, frontend and backend specialized in Go, Python, Javascript, Typescript, Django, React, Nextjs, DRF and vast GNU linux experience.</description>
      
    <item>
        <title>Common and Useful Deployment Patterns</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/common-and-useful-deployment-patterns/</link>
        <description>I explain some common deploy patterns</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Worker Pool Design Pattern Explanation</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/worker-pool-design-pattern-explanation/</link>
        <description>I explain how the worker pool design pattern works, the ideal job queue to handle with programming languages that support concurrency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Chat Gpt, Searle's Chinese Room and consciousness</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/chat-gpt-searles-chinese-room-and-consciousness/</link>
        <description>A brief introduction to the topic of consciousness, artifcial intelligence, chatGPT and the Chinese room by John Searle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go with Reflect: Discover How Reflect Can Boost Your Program's Flexibility</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-with-reflect-discover-how-reflect-can-boost-your-programs-flexibility/</link>
        <description>I explain the reflect package of go and its basic reflection functions to obtain data types at runtime</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Stream your videos and audios: A simple introduction to streaming with HLS for your applications</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/stream-your-videos-and-audios-a-simple-introduction-to-streaming-with-hls-for-your-applications/</link>
        <description>The HLS streaming protocol is responsible for splitting audio and video files into parts with extension ts and an index file with extension m3u8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Unleash Your API's Potential With gRPC and Protobuffers</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/unleash-your-apis-potential-with-grpc-and-protobuffers/</link>
        <description>What is a gRPC API and what are .proto files and protobuffers? What advantages do protobuffers have over JSON and what is the mechanism that makes them so efficient?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>I Test ChatGPT With Codewars Coding Challenges</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/i-test-chatgpt-with-codewars-coding-challenges/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go Migration Tutorial with migrate</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-migration-tutorial-with-migrate/</link>
        <description>In this tutorial I explain what are the migrations up, down of a database, as well as how to create and manage them using go's migrate library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: Handling Signals for Closing Applications</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-handling-signals-for-closing-applications/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Generating PDFs with Django and Reportlab</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/generating-pdfs-with-django-and-reportlab/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Azure AZ-900 Certification Exam: My Experience</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/azure-az-900-certification-exam-my-experience/</link>
        <description>I tell you about my experience taking the Microsoft Azure AZ-900 Fundamentals certification exam</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Dynamic sitemap with django</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/dynamic-sitemap-with-django/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Logging with the standard library in Go</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/logging-with-the-standard-library-in-go/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How Does a Docker Container Work Internally?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-does-a-docker-container-work-internally/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Autocomplete, Suggestions and Related Content: Solr and Django</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/autocomplete-suggestions-and-related-content-solr-and-django/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to implement Solr for searches or queries in Django?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-implement-solr-for-searches-or-queries-in-django/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Git Submodules and its Workflow</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/git-submodules-and-its-workflow/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Top 5 Favorite Algorithm Problems at Codewars</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/top-5-favorite-algorithm-problems-at-codewars/</link>
        <description>Learn how to use celery in django to schedule periodic or maintenance tasks to run every certain time or on a given date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>REST API: Best practices and design</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/rest-api-best-practices-and-design/</link>
        <description>Good practices for designing a REST API, how to version it, update it and nest resources in URIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>REST API basic characteristics and recommendations</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/rest-api-basic-characteristics-and-recommendations/</link>
        <description>What characteristics should a REST API meet? Diagonal at the end of the url or not? what is HATEOAS? do I use uppercase or lowercase in the url?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Categories in Django using ForeignKey to self</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/categories-in-django-using-foreignkey-to-self/</link>
        <description>Entry about using ForeignKey or foreign key to 'self' in Django to create hierarchical structures or unbounded categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Debounce and Throttle in Javascript</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/debounce-and-throttle-in-javascript/</link>
        <description>Explanation of debounce and throttle patterns applied to JavaScript, how they work and outline of how they work internally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to customize the User model in Django?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-customize-the-user-model-in-django/</link>
        <description>I explain how to customize the User model in Django to add extra fields or modify the default behavior of the Users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Differences between select_related and prefetch_related in Django</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/differences-between-select_related-and-prefetch_related-in-django/</link>
        <description>Difference and use of django's select_related and prefetch_related methods to reduce the number of queries or database queries</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Why using React.FC could be a bad practice?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/why-using-reactfc-could-be-a-bad-practice/</link>
        <description>In this post I talk about the reasons why some developers claim that React.FC is a bad practice in React and Typescript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: profiling or basic profiling of CPU usage</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-profiling-or-basic-profiling-of-cpu-usage/</link>
        <description>Entry on go code profiling, line-by-line impact analysis and export of results to web and pdf format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: basic testing and coverage</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-basic-testing-and-coverage/</link>
        <description>Entry on basic testing in go: creating tests, handling multiple cases, coverage and exporting results to html.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: race conditions on goroutines and mutexes</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-race-conditions-on-goroutines-and-mutexes/</link>
        <description>In this post I talk about race conditions that occur when using goroutines and how to prevent them by using mutex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: channels, understanding the goroutines deadlocks</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-channels-understanding-the-goroutines-deadlocks/</link>
        <description>In this post I deal with deadlocks in go, the causes of the fatal error error: all goroutines are asleep - deadlock! and how to prevent it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: use of channels to communicate goroutines</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-use-of-channels-to-communicate-goroutines/</link>
        <description>undefined</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: introduction to goroutines and concurrency</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-introduction-to-goroutines-and-concurrency/</link>
        <description>Post about the basics of goroutines, channels or channels, waitgroups and locks in the golang or go programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: package import and module management</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-package-import-and-module-management/</link>
        <description>Learn the basics of importing packages and handling modules in the go programming language. Master the go init method and the go.mod file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: Structs, inheritance, polymorphism and encapsulation</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-structs-inheritance-polymorphism-and-encapsulation/</link>
        <description>Declares structs in go and emulates the inheritance, polymorphism and encapsulation that are present in object-oriented programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: string runes and bytes explained</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-string-runes-and-bytes-explained/</link>
        <description>In this post I explain a bit about the differences between strings, runes and bytes in the go programming language and their basic usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: maps o dictionaries</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-maps-o-dictionaries/</link>
        <description>I explain how a map works in go or golang and learn how to declare them, create them explicitly with make and traverse them with range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: slices y arrays, characteristicas and basic uses</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-slices-y-arrays-characteristicas-and-basic-uses/</link>
        <description>Syntax and basic uses of arrays and slices in the go programming language. I also explain how to use the make function in slices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: cycles or loops for, break, continue, defer, if and else</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-cycles-or-loops-for-break-continue-defer-if-and-else/</link>
        <description>Syntax and basic uses of if and else structures, loops, their types, break, continue and defer in the go programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go: functions, arguments and the fmt package</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-functions-arguments-and-the-fmt-package/</link>
        <description>Learn the basic syntax, returns, return types, multiple arguments and use of the fmt package of the go programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Go, programming language, introduction to variables and data types</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/go-programming-language-introduction-to-variables-and-data-types/</link>
        <description>Learn the basics of the go or golang programming language: compilation, file structure, variables and data types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Django channels: channel layers, groups and users</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/django-channels-channel-layers-groups-and-users/</link>
        <description>Implement channel layers in your django channels app to share information between channels or channels/consumers and groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Django channels: consumers, environments and events</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/django-channels-consumers-environments-and-events/</link>
        <description>Learn the basics of django channels: consumers, scope and events, to handle websockets (ws) requests and return responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Python vs Go Which is the Best?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/python-vs-go-which-is-the-best/</link>
        <description>Learn about the differences, features and similarities between Python and Go (Golang), two languages used for web development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Graphql and django with graphene</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/graphql-and-django-with-graphene/</link>
        <description>How to implement graphql queries and mutations in a django project, using the models and its ORM using graphene? I explain you here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Types for React components with children</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/types-for-react-components-with-children/</link>
        <description>Three different ways to set types in typescript for components that receive children as a parameter in React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to measure requests per second with locust in python?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-measure-requests-per-second-with-locust-in-python/</link>
        <description>Learn how to perform and customize user traffic audits and requests per second (rps) reality using locust in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Facebook's plugin chat how to decrease its impact?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/facebooks-plugin-chat-how-to-decrease-its-impact/</link>
        <description>Prevent the facebook chat online plugin from slowing down the loading of your page, and affecting the web vitals indicators, delaying its loading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>OCR with tesseract, python and pytesseract</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/ocr-with-tesseract-python-and-pytesseract/</link>
        <description>Learn how to perform optical character recognition (OCR) on images using python, tesseract-ocr and pytesseract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Python tortoise ORM integration with FastAPI</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/python-tortoise-orm-integration-with-fastapi/</link>
        <description>Tortoise is a Python ORM that you can integrate with fastAPI to create models and handle SQL queries with various databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The django admin panel and its customization</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/the-django-admin-panel-and-its-customization/</link>
        <description>Learn how to customize the behavior of the django admin panel in an application, sort fields, omit fields or change its appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Caching in Django REST Framework using memcached</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/caching-in-django-rest-framework-using-memcached/</link>
        <description>Learn how to implement and configure different levels of caching in your Django REST Framework application using memcached as a backend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Periodic Tasks with Celery and Django</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/periodic-tasks-with-celery-and-django/</link>
        <description>Learn how to use celery in django to schedule periodic or maintenance tasks to run every so often or on a given date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Celery and django to run asynchronous tasks</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/celery-and-django-to-run-asynchronous-tasks/</link>
        <description>Celery allows asynchronous task execution in django. Configure celery in django to handle time-consuming mails or computations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Login using Django Rest Framework DRF</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/login-using-django-rest-framework-drf/</link>
        <description>Implement login and registration of your users in django with the dj-rest-auth and django-allauth libraries using tokens and also JWT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>React memo, useMemo and useCallback to avoid React renderings</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/react-memo-usememo-and-usecallback-to-avoid-react-renderings/</link>
        <description>Use the React hook useCallback and its HOC memo to improve the performance of your application by avoiding renderings in your components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>React useCallback, useMemo and memo, differences and uses</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/react-usecallback-usememo-and-memo-differences-and-uses/</link>
        <description>Learn the differences between the useCallback and useMemo hooks, and the HOC memo in React and how to improve your app's performance with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Mexico Postal codes API with Django</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/mexico-postal-codes-api-with-django/</link>
        <description>Creates a Mexico postal code API that returns colonias, state and municipality, with SEPOMEX data using this Django library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Django and htmx, modern web apps without writing JS</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/django-and-htmx-modern-web-apps-without-writing-js/</link>
        <description>Learn how to combine Django and htmx to create websites, keep the same functionalities with much less client-side JS code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Django Rest Framework and JWT to authenticate users</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/django-rest-framework-and-jwt-to-authenticate-users/</link>
        <description>Learn how to implement basic authentication in Django using JWT and Django Rest Framework via access and refresh tokens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Managers or custom handlers in Django</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/managers-or-custom-handlers-in-django/</link>
        <description>I explain what a manager is, what it's for and how you can create and customize them to get the most out of them when using Django's ORM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Trigrams and advanced searches with Django and Postgres</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/trigrams-and-advanced-searches-with-django-and-postgres/</link>
        <description>I show you the basics of advanced text searches using trigrams and similarity indices and others, using Django and Postgres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Full text search and searches with Django and Postgres</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/full-text-search-and-searches-with-django-and-postgres/</link>
        <description>Learn about the basic search methods that Django and Postgres have to offer, as well as full text search and other advanced features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Ngrok, your localhost accessible from the internet</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/ngrok-your-localhost-accessible-from-the-internet/</link>
        <description>Ngrok makes your localhost public, either for testing your endpoint responses or showing progress to your customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How do permissions and permissions groups work in Django?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-do-permissions-and-permissions-groups-work-in-django/</link>
        <description>Learn how to create permissions, groups, assign them to users, and create custom permissions in Django. Even if you've never done it before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Don't make this mistake using arrays in Python</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/dont-make-this-mistake-using-arrays-in-python/</link>
        <description>Why is it that when I change one element of an array in a Python array all the others are changed? I explain why it happens and how to prevent it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to upload multiple images in Django?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-upload-multiple-images-in-django/</link>
        <description>Learn how to handle uploading multiple images in Django and returning them in JSON format, ideal for consuming an API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Why should you use Django Framework?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/why-should-you-use-django-framework/</link>
        <description>Is Django worth using in a world where everything is JavaScript? Enter to learn about the advantages and disadvantages of this Python framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Throttling on Nginx</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/throttling-on-nginx/</link>
        <description>Learn how to use Throttling in Nginx to limit the number of requests in your application, mitigating DDOS or brute force attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to make a switch in Python?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-make-a-switch-in-python/</link>
        <description>Learn how to use the Python switch statement called match, its basic syntax and guard, to control the flow of your application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>5 cool React libraries you should know about</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/5-cool-react-libraries-you-should-know-about/</link>
        <description>I show you some of my favorite React related libraries, and some videos so you can see them in action working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>What is Django genericForeignkey for?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/what-is-django-genericforeignkey-for/</link>
        <description>Learn how to use ContentType and the genericForeignKey field type in Django to relate an object to different model types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>What does the ContentType application do in Django?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/what-does-the-contenttype-application-do-in-django/</link>
        <description>Learn what ContentType is for in Django and how to access the information this model stores in our Django app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to create a command in django?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-create-a-command-in-django/</link>
        <description>I explain how to create a command from django, the Python web development framework, using positional and optional arguments from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Digital Ocean, analysis and my experience as a user</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/digital-ocean-analysis-and-my-experience-as-a-user/</link>
        <description>In this post I talk about my experience using the Digital Ocean platform, as well as the options it has to offer you as a developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Is your Django application slow? Maximize its performance with these tips</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/is-your-django-application-slow-maximize-its-performance-with-these-tips/</link>
        <description>Maximize the performance of your app made in Django with this compilation of tips ranging from your queries, to caching, to alternative frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Python vs Javascript which one is better?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/python-vs-javascript-which-one-is-better/</link>
        <description>Learn the differences between Python and Javascript, two of the most popular languages. Syntax, speed, packages, frameworks available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to create a history of visited products with django and redis?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-create-a-history-of-visited-products-with-django-and-redis/</link>
        <description>Learn how to create step by step a history of visited products using the django framework and the redis database engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Django Annotate and aggregate explained</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/django-annotate-and-aggregate-explained/</link>
        <description>Learn the differences, features and usage of annotate and aggregate in Django in this tutorial, reading SQL with examples and code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Nginx keepalive, gzip, http2: better performance on your website</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/nginx-keepalive-gzip-http2-better-performance-on-your-website/</link>
        <description>Optimize your website and make it faster by enabling http2, gzip compression, cache and modifying the keepalive value in nginx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>FastAPI tutorial, the best Python framework?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/fastapi-tutorial-the-best-python-framework/</link>
        <description>Enter here to learn the basics of Python fastAPI, the new Python web framework that achieves super fast and efficient APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Cookiecutter-django for configuring and deploying in Django</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/cookiecutter-django-for-configuring-and-deploying-in-django/</link>
        <description>Don't know how to use or what a cookiecutter is for in Django? Come in and learn for free how to use this tool that will make your life easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Get to know the basic Docker Compose commands</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/get-to-know-the-basic-docker-compose-commands/</link>
        <description>In this Docker compose tutorial I explain the most common commands, as well as the structure and creation of a docker-compose.yml file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The basic Docker commands and their usage</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/the-basic-docker-commands-and-their-usage/</link>
        <description>Learn how to use basic Docker commands, differentiate images and containers, volumes, create Dockerfiles and use docker build.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>What is Docker and what is it for?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/what-is-docker-and-what-is-it-for/</link>
        <description>Do you think using Docker doesn't make sense? Do you think Docker and virtual machines are the same? Come in and I'll explain the differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Understand inheritance types in Django models</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/understand-inheritance-types-in-django-models/</link>
        <description>I explain three types of inheritance in Django models: abstract, multi-table and proxy, as well as their characteristics and syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to convert jpg to webp on GNU Linux?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-convert-jpg-to-webp-on-gnu-linux/</link>
        <description>A couple of weeks ago I wanted to convert my ecommerce images from jpg to webp. Normally to modify images in GNU/Linux I use GIMP...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Learning Django through the book Django by example, my review</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/learning-django-through-the-book-django-by-example-my-review/</link>
        <description>Here is my review of the book Django by Example, a book to learn Django from scratch through simple projects. Come in and read it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Get to know bat in linux, the syntax highlighting cat</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/get-to-know-bat-in-linux-the-syntax-highlighting-cat/</link>
        <description>A few days ago I discovered bat, it's the linux version of cat with syntax highlighting that makes reading files in console more comfortable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Pipenv: The virtual environment manager you DON'T know</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/pipenv-the-virtual-environment-manager-you-dont-know/</link>
        <description>I teach you how to install Pipenv, create a Pipfile, set environment variables and what you need to know about this virtual environment manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Django 3.1 changes and new features: complete overview</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/django-31-changes-and-new-features-complete-overview/</link>
        <description>In this post I talk about the changes and new features in Django 3.1. Django 3.1 includes asynchronous support for middleware, views and a JSON field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Learn Python through cryptography my review of Cracking codes with Python</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/learn-python-through-cryptography-my-review-of-cracking-codes-with-python/</link>
        <description>Cracking Codes with Python is a book to learn the basics of Python while giving a practical overview of the history of cryptography. My review here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Secure passwords, keepassxc tutorial</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/secure-passwords-keepassxc-tutorial/</link>
        <description>keepassxc tutorial. Achieve secure and impenetrable passwords by brute force, even if you don't know anything about cryptography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to create a secure password?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-create-a-secure-password/</link>
        <description>Learn how to create a secure password that protects your personal accounts, and those of your clients, from cybercriminals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Python Design Patterns, review of Practical Python Design Patterns</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/python-design-patterns-review-of-practical-python-design-patterns/</link>
        <description>Learn Python design patterns with the book Practical Python Design Patterns, even if you've never read about the subject before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Is Code Commenting Wrong? Clean Code Review</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/is-code-commenting-wrong-clean-code-review/</link>
        <description>In this review I will talk a bit about Clean Code, the book by Robert C. Martin that explains how to write code cleanly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The best Django book, Two Scoops of Django review</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/the-best-django-book-two-scoops-of-django-review/</link>
        <description>This is a review of Two scoops of Django. A book focused on good development practices for the open source web development framework Django.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Django for Professionals' review</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/django-for-professionals-review/</link>
        <description>Django for professionals is one of the modern books about the Django web development framework. This post is my take on the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The definitive guide to Django</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/the-definitive-guide-to-django/</link>
        <description>My review of the free Spanish-language definitive guide to Django from the book. The definitive guide to Django, by the co-creators of Django</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to program an automatic wallpaper changer in Python?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-program-an-automatic-wallpaper-changer-in-python/</link>
        <description>How to schedule an automatic wallpaper changer in GNU/Linux using Python? In this entry we will use Cron to change the wallpaper every so often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to create an automatic wallpaper changer using Python in Gnome?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-create-an-automatic-wallpaper-changer-using-python-in-gnome/</link>
        <description>Program a lightweight, minimalistic and fairly simple wallpaper changer for Gnome on GNU/Linux using Python from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Cron and Crontab schedules recurring tasks</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/cron-and-crontab-schedules-recurring-tasks/</link>
        <description>Learn how to use crontab to schedule repetitive tasks such as database backups, sending emails, periodically on GNU/Linux using Cron and Crontab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>You are misusing console.log in javascript</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/you-are-misusing-consolelog-in-javascript/</link>
        <description>Learn at once how to take advantage of the javascript console object and its most useful methods to make your development easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Destructuring with default values in Javascript</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/destructuring-with-default-values-in-javascript/</link>
        <description>Do you want to know how to understand how to perform destructuring an object with default values in javascript from scratch? In this post I explain how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Destructuring of nested objects</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/destructuring-of-nested-objects/</link>
        <description>Destructuring nested objects in javascript? In this post I discuss the topic of destructuring nested objects with examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Destructuring lists in JavaScript</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/destructuring-lists-in-javascript/</link>
        <description>Learn and understand perfectly the destructuring of lists in javascript. In this post I explain the topic with examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Destructuring variables in javascript</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/destructuring-variables-in-javascript/</link>
        <description>In this post I am going to try to explain in a simple way the destructuring of objects in javascript. Destructuring is a process that, despite what is believed, is actually quite simple and can improve code readability quite a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The best book for learning modern JavaScript</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/the-best-book-for-learning-modern-javascript/</link>
        <description>If you plan to spend a few hours learning javascript, don't waste your time looking for more, you will hardly find a book that covers such a variety of concepts in such an understandable and complete way as this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The 4chan about technology and programming</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/the-4chan-about-technology-and-programming/</link>
        <description>In this post I give my opinion about one of the most popular programming and technology image boards out there, lainchan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>How to find a previously executed command in GNU Linux?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/how-to-find-a-previously-executed-command-in-gnu-linux/</link>
        <description>Has it ever happened to you that you want to find a previously executed command in GNU/Linux. There are several ways to do it, here I explain two of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>The Big O notation</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/the-big-o-notation/</link>
        <description>I explain what Big O notation is all about so you can improve the efficiency of your algorithms in your applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Learn Python from scratch with this free book</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/learn-python-from-scratch-with-this-free-book/</link>
        <description>Enter here to read my review of an excellent free book to learn Python, which is also fully translated into Spanish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Python virtualenv linux basic tutorial</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/python-virtualenv-linux-basic-tutorial/</link>
        <description>Learn how to user virtualenv on GNU/Linux, the best known python tool for managing virtual environments visit this tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Why should you use a virtual environment in python?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/why-should-you-use-a-virtual-environment-in-python/</link>
        <description>Don't know what a virtual environment in Python is? Here I explain what it is, what it's for and its differences with virtual machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Learn python from scratch Beginning Python Review</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/learn-python-from-scratch-beginning-python-review/</link>
        <description>This post is a brief review of Beginning Python: From Novice To Professional, a book with which to learn Python from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>To program a blog or to use wordpress?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/to-program-a-blog-or-to-use-wordpress/</link>
        <description>Many times we face the doubt of programming a blog from scratch or using a more popular solution like wordpress. In this post I explain my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Testing with tox in Python, tutorial from scratch</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/testing-with-tox-in-python-tutorial-from-scratch/</link>
        <description>Learn that it is tox, as it is installed, as tox.ini files are used and how to configure it to create safer tests in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Unittest python are python tests worthwhile?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/unittest-python-are-python-tests-worthwhile/</link>
        <description>Tests are a waste, right? Go here and learn about unittest, coverage, mock and other popular python tools for testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>An Algorithm Problem a Day</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/an-algorithm-problem-a-day/</link>
        <description>Want to practice one algorithm problem a day for your job interviews? Check out this free page to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Understand permissions in GNU Linux and the chmod command</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/understand-permissions-in-gnu-linux-and-the-chmod-command/</link>
        <description>Understand at once how the chmod command works, in charge of assigning permissions in GNU/Linux to folders and files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Linux Commands you should know (part three)</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/linux-commands-you-should-know-part-three/</link>
        <description>Learn the basic GNU/Linux terminal commands, in this post I talk about printenv, systemctl, top, ps, chown, chmod and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Linux commands you should know (part two)</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/linux-commands-you-should-know-part-two/</link>
        <description>Learn about the basic GNU/Linux commands offered by the terminal, for this entry I explain uname, who, du, df, among many others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Basic Linux commands you should know</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/basic-linux-commands-you-should-know/</link>
        <description>The GNU/Linux terminal has a lot of useful commands, learn the basics here, even if you have never used the terminal before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>My experience using EasyWP and namecheap</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/my-experience-using-easywp-and-namecheap/</link>
        <description>Thinking about using easywp? Log in to read my experience using easywp application to host a blog on namecheap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
        <title>Hello World, how did I learn to code?</title>
        <link>https://eduardozepeda.dev/blog/hello-world-how-did-i-learn-to-code/</link>
        <description>This is a personal entry where I explain how I learned to program for the first time, first in PHP and my first contacts with Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    </channel>
    
    </rss> 